(戴尔·阿诺食品  把丰收带回家)
(一号板子  雷吉·门罗)
小镇被攻陷了
The town was overrun.
他和尼古拉斯先走了
He split off with Nicholas.
他认为...
He had this idea that...
如果他放火  就能阻止行尸过来
if he lit a fire, it would stop the walkers from coming here.
我说过换我去
I tried to go instead.
我想去的
I wanted to.
火一直没有点起来
The fire never got lit.
我们不得不走了
We had to keep going.
我真抱歉
I'm sorry.
他说如果他被困住了
He said if he got stuck,
他会想办法给我们发信号
he would find a way to send us a signal.
信号
A signal?
开门
Open the gate!
快开门
Open the gate now!
《行尸走肉》
你们能听见
You can hear it.
有些人看见了
Some of you saw it.
有一半的行尸回来了
They got back here, half of them.
足够把我们死死围住
Still enough to surround us 20 deep.
我知道你们很害怕
Look, I know you're scared.
你们没见过这种事
You haven't seen anything like this.
你们没经历过这种事
You haven't been through anything like this.
但我们目前是安全的
But we're safe for now.
卡车撞上的板子好像没有受损
The panel the truck hit seems intact.
我们加固了它  以防万一
We reinforced it just in case.
不管怎么样  墙都能支撑住
Either way, the wall's gonna hold together.
你们能吗
Can you?
其余的人会回来的
The others, they're gonna be back.
他们会回来的
They're gonna be back.
达里尔  亚伯拉罕  萨沙  他们有车
Daryl, Abraham, Sasha, they have vehicles.
他们会引走行尸  就跟另一半一样
They're gonna lead 'em away, just like the others.
格伦和尼古拉斯
And Glenn and Nicholas are
之后会从前门回来
gonna walk back through the front gate after.
他们知道自己在做什么
They know what they're doing,
我们也知道我们该做什么
and we know what we need to do.
我们尽量不要出声
We keep noise to a minimum.
晚上拉上百叶窗
Pull our blinds at night.
最好别开灯
Even better, keep the lights out.
我们尽量让这地方
We'll try to make this place
像墓地一样安静  看看行尸会不会离开
as quiet as a graveyard, see if they move on.
这地方就是个墓地
This place is a graveyard.
采石场的缺口开了
The quarry broke open
那些行尸在往这边走
and those walkers were heading this way.
所有的行尸
All of them.
瑞克安排的计划
The plan that Rick put into place
阻止了那一切的发生
stopped that from happening.
他引开了一半行尸
He got half of them away.
我之前跟达里尔一起出去招人
I was out there recruiting with Daryl.
我想进入罐头厂找点补给
I wanted to try to get into a cannery and scavenge,
而达里尔想继续找人
and Daryl wanted to keep looking for people.
我们做了我想做的事
We did what I wanted...
最后落入了那些人的陷阱之中
and we wound up in a trap set by those people.
我丢了背包
And I lost my pack.
他们一定是跟踪了我们
They must've followed our tracks.
攻击我们的那些人
Those people who attacked us...
是因为我  他们才找到了过来的路
they found their way back here because of me.
其他事我们以后再谈
There'll be more to talk about.
迪安娜
Deanna?
别
Don't.
我们不在墙内埋葬杀人凶手
We don't bury killers inside the walls.
我们又不能出去
We aren't going out there.
那该怎么办
So what do we do?
我们等着
We wait.
这点材料都不够我做两餐
I can't even make two meals out of this.
多掺点水就能把汤和酱料煮成一大锅
The soups and sauces can be stretched out with some extra water.
假如我们明天就死了
What difference does that make
这样做又有什么用呢
if we'll be dead tomorrow?
-现在得定量配给  -我做不到
- We have to ration now-- - I can't.
我没办法在剩下的时间里看着家人挨饿
I can't spend whatever time I have left watching my family starve.
-等等  -抱歉
- Wait. - I'm sorry.
抱歉  奥利维亚
Sorry, Olivia.
我觉得没有意义
I just don't see the point.
住手
Stop.
马上  住手
Right now, stop it.
这些东西是要供给所有人的
This stuff is for everyone.
要想活命我们必须从长计议
We need to make it last if we're gonna survive.
你为何不去确认一下大门关好了  斯宾塞
Why don't you go make sure the gate's closed, Spencer?
没错  那怪我
Yeah. That was me.
是我干的
I did that.
但墙外的那辆卡车
But that truck outside the walls,
要不是我  它就冲进来了
it'd be inside if it wasn't for me.
那也是我干的
I did that, too.
要不是我
If I didn't,
也许我们现在就没办法在这谈话了
maybe we wouldn't be talking right now.
而你当时在哪呢  布鲁斯
Where were you, Bruce?
这么做会让我们踏上无所忌惮之路
Doing this will start us down a road where nothing matters.
不在乎任何人
Where no one else matters.
然后当我们毁了这个地方后
And then we'll all look back at this moment right now
我们都会回首这一刻
as when we destroyed this place.
(大卫  斯特奇斯  阿德里安  尼古拉斯  格伦)
你要出去吗
You're going out?
手电筒  钢筋  绳子
The flashlights, the rebar, the rope.
你在远处把它们放下墙
You lower them off the wall a good distance apart,
也许转一转它们
maybe spin them.
那样  行尸就会被吸引过去
That way, the walkers are drawn to each one
为你开一条路
and you open up a path.
现在你在做准备
Now you're gearing up.
就等着天黑了  是不是
Just waiting for dark, right?
你跳下去时扭到脚怎么办
What happens when you twist an ankle jumping down?
或者你被一个行尸缠住
Or you just get slowed down by one of them
然后得应对所有行尸
and then you have to deal with all of them?
我不能让你这么做
I can't let you do this.
你阻止不了我
You can't stop me.
我打算帮你
I'm going to help you.
我知道一条更安全的出路
And I know a safer way out.
(农作物  玉米)
(大麦  苜蓿)
(小麦)
(磨坊)
(教育  训练)
(指导纲领  选举)
(教育  训练  贸易  医学  知识  安保)
(电力)
(扩张)
(探索)
(总有一天  你所承受过的痛苦会有助于你)
-斯宾塞  -是我
- Spencer? - Yeah.
我...
I...
是我不好
My bad.
你喝醉了吗
Are you drunk?
快了
Getting there.
是从储藏室拿的吧
This came from the pantry.
你偷的吗
You-- you stole it?
别说得那么难听
I wouldn't call it that.
那你跟大家说的
So what you told everyone...
都是屁话不成
that was just bullshit?
不  如果他们都去抢储藏室
No. If they all went in and raided the pantry and
被大家知道  看到
everyone knew it, saw it,
那就完了
then that would be the end.
但如果只有一个人
But one person?
那么谁也不会知道
One person, and no one ever would know.
所以  为什么不是我呢
So, why not me?
我阻止了劫掠食物
I stopped that little run at the bank.
我应该得到些奖励
I deserve a reward.
一次最后的庆祝
One last celebration.
因为他们是对的  妈
Because they were right, Mom,
你知道的
and you know it.
我们很快都会死的
We're all gonna be dead real soon.
该死  斯宾塞
Damn it, Spencer!
你怪我
Me?
你现在说的才是屁话
Now that is some bullshit!
都是因为你  我们才会玩完
You're the reason we're so screwed.
是你让我们变成这样的
You made us this way.
我们在这里从没有安全过
We were never safe here.
而你只想自欺欺人
But you didn't want to see that.
你只想欺骗我们
You didn't want us to see that.
你只想做白日梦
You just wanted to dream.
爸爸和艾登身上发生的事
What happened to Dad, to Aiden,
都是你的错
that's all you.
你还好吗
You okay?
为什么不好呢
Why wouldn't I be?
看到伊妮德了吗
Have you seen Enid?
看到她跟你在一起后就没见过了
Not since I saw her with you.
我想她在尸群到来之前翻墙出去了
I think she went over the wall just before the herd came and
现在她被困在外面了
now she's trapped out there.
你怎么知道她没死
What makes you think she isn't dead?
拜托  伙计
Come on, man.
听着
Look...
我要去找她
I'll go find her.
我需要你的帮助
I just need your help.
-如果你能爬到...  -我不会帮你的  卡尔
- If you maybe climb up-- - I'm not helping you, Carl.
这不是为了我
This isn't for me.
是为了伊妮德
It's for Enid.
-你的朋友  -我的女朋友
- Your friend. - My girlfriend.
我是说  反正她曾经是  对吗
Or, I mean, 'cause she was any way, right?
你就这么不管她了吗
So you want to just leave her out there?
我警告过她不要翻墙出去
I told her to stop going over the wall,
我告诉过她外面有坏人
I told her there's bad people out there
那么做很蠢很危险
and that it's stupid and dangerous.
除非你知道自己在做什么
Not if you know what you're doing.
我不会让你去的
Well, I'm not gonna let you go.
卡尔
Carl.
卡尔  你不能出去
Carl, you're not going out there.
走开
Back off.
好吧
All right.
我去告诉你爸
I'll tell your dad.
他会出去找你  其他人也会
He'll go out there to find you, then other people will, too.
然后就会有人送命
And then somebody's gonna die.
你救过我的命  现在我在救你
You saved my life and now I'm saving yours.
抱歉
Sorry.
不小心手滑了
Got away from me.
你还在这里
You're still here.
别
Don't.
好吧
'Kay.
我也不会夸你勇敢
Won't tell you you're being brave, either.
他还没醒  他的伤口已经感染了
He hasn't woken up. His wound's infected.
我不知道该怎么办
I don't know what the hell to do,
所以无论我怎么样都没意义
so it doesn't really matter what I'm being.
是啊  可是你还在这里
Yeah, but you're still here.
你来干什么
Why are you here?
我头疼
My head hurts.
按1到10级算  有多疼
On a scale of one to 10, how bad?
我骗你呢
I'm lying.
我只是想来看看你
I'm just checking on you.
我就这样
Here I am.
茫然地坐在地上
Clueless on the floor.
你给别人包扎了伤口
You patched people up.
你在努力帮助大家
You're...You're helping make things better.
我觉得他会死
I think he's gonna die.
这里发生的事已经够吓人了
And I'm so scared about what's happening in here
我都不敢想外边发生了什么
that I can't think about what's happening out there.
其实这是好事
And that's actually good.
我也不知道该怎么应对
And I don't know what to do with that.
我只想让他活下去  让行尸离开
I just want him to live and for the roamers to go away.
想让一名真正的医生出现在门口
And for a doctor to show up at the gates
那样我就能回到自己的屋子里
so I can go back to my apartment
继续看《战争与和平》了
and keep reading "War and Peace."
然而现在是世界末日
But here comes the end of the world.
他还没死呢
He's not dead yet.
那可不好说
I don't know about that.
我并不是感受不到
It's not like I don't feel it.
害怕的滋味不好受
You know, being afraid sucks.
我曾经不想面对
I used to not want to see...
现实
the way things are.
倒不是我没有能力面对
It's not that I couldn't.
而是我不想面对
It's that I-- I didn't want to.
但现在的生活就是这样
But this is what life looks like now.
我们必须面对
We have to see it.
我们必须抗争
We have to fight it.
如果不抗争  我们就会死
If we don't fight, we die.
你不是说不用翻过去吗
I thought you said we weren't going over.
的确不用
We're not.
我们从地下过去
We're going under.
这个入口通向一个
This leads to a sewer
旧住宅区的下水道
that was part of the old neighborhood
存在于亚历山大建成之前
that was here before they built this up.
我们可以通过它从墙下边走
It'll take us under the wall...
但愿能绕过行尸
and hopefully past the walkers.
多谢
Thanks...
但剩下的路我一个人走
but I'm going on my own from here.
-玛姬...  -不
- Maggie... - No.
求你了
Please.
我不想再看到任何人的名字被写到墙上
I can't-- I can't watch more names go up on that wall.
-如果他还活着...  -如果吗
- If he's alive-- - If?
他跟米琼恩说过如果他能逃出来
He told Michonne he would've found
就会想办法给我们发信号
some way to signal us if he got out.
如果他还活着  或者受伤
If he's alive or he's hurt
被困  被人抓走
or trapped, maybe taken.
如果他还活着  他就需要我的帮助
If he's alive, he needs my help.
所以我才要这么做
That's why I'm doing this.
如果他死了  我也不想傻傻地等着
And if he's dead, I don't want to be waiting on him.
这些都不是你的错  你没必要这样做
None of this is your fault. You don't need to do this.
很多人都死了
People are dead.
这有我的责任
I was a part of that.
我必须背负着这份罪孽活下去
And I have to live with that.
灾变后我就没有来过这里
I haven't been down here since the beginning.
这梯子肯定很早以前就倒了
This ladder must've fallen a long time ago.
我们试试搬开
Let's try and get it out of here.
-好的  -我数到三
- Yeah. - On three, ready?
一  二  三
One, two, three.
亚伦
Aaron!
我没事  被梯子绊了一跤
I'm okay. The ladder caught me.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
亚伦
Aaron...
你的头
your head.
过来
Come here.
可能需要缝针  亚伦  回去吧
This could need stitches. Aaron, just go back.
-不  -快回去
- No. - Yes.
-我刚救过你  -我一个人也能应付
- I was just there for you. - I could have done it.
带路吧
Just lead the way.
行吗
Please?
天啊
Hot damn.
达里尔  萨沙  亚伯拉罕  收到了吗
Daryl, Sasha, Abraham, you copy?
瑞克
Rick?
我能上来吗
Can I come up?
可以
Yeah.
你还没见过
You haven't seen it.
是啊
No.
伊妮德  她...
Enid, she, uh...
她以前喜欢溜到墙外
she used to sneak over the walls,
在外面待一会儿
spend time out there.
我不知道为什么  她就是想出去
You know, I don't know why. She just wanted to.
但是...
But, um...
我觉得袭击发生后她又出去了
I think she went out there after the attack.
什么  她还在外面吗
What, she's still out there?
是的
Yeah.
我们不知道她在哪里
We don't know where she is.
但她知道该如何照顾好自己
You know, but she knows how to take care of herself.
我们不能出去
And we can't go out there.
卡尔想试试
Carl wanted to try.
我阻止了他
I stopped him.
我跟他说  如果他敢出去我就告诉你
I told him I'd tell you if he did.
然后  我也说不清
And then, um-- I don't know.
我只是觉得应该告诉你
I just thought I should tell you--
你知道他现在在哪吗
Do you know where he is now?
知道  他现在回到屋子里了
Yeah, he's back at the house.
我看见他跟朱迪思在门廊
I saw him on the porch with Judith.
你愿意的话  我可以来看守
I can keep guard, if you want.
那下面  有它们在看守这个地方
Down there, they're guarding the place now.
这只是为了留心还没回来的那些人
This is just about keeping an eye out for the others that aren't back,
看看有没有格伦的信号
looking for a sign from Glenn.
好的
All right.
谢谢
Thank you.
我在想你之前在采石场说的话
So I was thinking about what you said back at the quarry.
你说的没错
And, uh, I mean, you're right.
我得学会保护自己
I need to know how to protect myself
保护我妈妈和弟弟
and my mom and brother.
还有这个地方
This place.
所以你能教我怎么开枪吗
So can you teach me how to shoot?
那就是你的靶子
There's your target.
放松
Just relax.
他怎么样
How is he?
为什么
What is it?
因为是世界末日
It's the end of the world.
不  不是的
No, it's not.
没错  害怕的滋味不好受
Yeah, being afraid sucks.
我们还是太近了
We're still too close.
我们只需穿过几个行尸就行了
We just have to get through a few them, then we're gone.
不
No.
准备好了吗
You ready?
不能这样
No, we can't.
你可以留下  我去
You can stay. I'll go.
不
No.
No!
-玛姬  -都结束了
- Maggie. - It's over!
我把他的最后一张照片烧了
I burned his last picture of him
因为我说我不再需要照片了
because I said I wasn't gonna need it anymore.
因为我不会再离开他半步
Because I was never gonna be away from him again.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
他不想让我去外面  我答应了
He didn't want me to go out there and I said yes.
我要是去了
And if I would've gone...
我要是跟他一块去了  或许能帮上他
if I was with him, maybe I could've helped him.
我不知道他是死是活
I don't know if he's alive.
米琼恩说他早该发信号了
He would've shown me by now. That's what Michonne said.
我只想看到他的脸
I just want to see his face.
但我看不到
I can't.
我无法预知将要发生的事情
I don't get to know what will happen.
我也没法知道为什么会发生
I won't get to know why it happened,
或是我做的是对是错
what I did right or wrong.
现在不行
Not now.
我得接受这一切  你也一样
I have to live with that. You do, too.
山姆  我给你做了饼干
Sam, I made you some cookies.
能请你拿到楼上来吗
Could you bring them up here, please?
不行  山姆
No, Sam.
为什么
Why?
你为什么不想下楼
Why don't you wanna come downstairs?
就是不想下楼
I just don't wanna go down there.
为什么
Why?
我只是
I just...
上面没什么变化
it didn't change up here.
我都上了一多半台阶了
Well, I'm more than halfway up,
所以我算是在楼上了
so technically I'm upstairs.
你到这里不算是楼下
You can come here and you won't be downstairs.
不  那算了
No, it's okay, then.
我这样说是因为事实如此
I'm going to talk that way because that's how it is!
这我知道  但你不能...
It is now, I know, but you can't--
全都是谎言
It was all a lie.
我们能活到现在  简直是个笑话
The fact that we're alive-- it's a joke.
这一切...
All this...
来吧  你这混蛋
Come on, you son of a bitch.
卡萝尔说她重伤了他们中一人
Carol said she got one of them,
但是她找不到尸体
but she couldn't find the body.
他一定在那下面
He must have been under there.
我想活下去
I want to live.
我想让这个地方存在下去
I want this place to stay standing.
你得领导他们
You need to lead them.
他们不需要我  瑞克
They don't need me, Rick.
他们需要的是你
What they need is you.
我对这个地方的设想
What I wanted for this place,
真的只是空中楼阁吗
was it really just pie in the sky?
不是
No.
我马上回来
I'll be right back.
等他回来以后  记得给他说
When he gets back, it's worth mentioning
亚伦 艾琳
that Aaron, Erin,
男女通用
works for a boy or a girl,
根据拼写不同
depending on the spelling.
我就说说
Just saying.
干嘛
What?
我来换班
I'm your relief.
不是卡萝尔吗
I thought Carol was up.
是她  我自愿替她
She was. I volunteered to take her place.
我从没机会说过  但是
You know, I never got a chance to say it, but...
卡车那事你做得很好
you did good with the truck,
干掉司机
taking out the driver.
如果不是你
You know, if it weren't for you,
墙现在也许不会立着
this wall might not be standing right now.
我只是走运
I just got lucky.
做得好或走运  并不重要
Good or lucky, it doesn't really matter.
你只用继续做你所做的事就行了
Just keep doing what you're doing.
墓地的那些尸体
Those bodies by the graveyard...
我之所以想等
the reason I wanted to wait was...
是为了格伦
was Glenn.
我们不知道他是否还活着
We don't know if he's still out there.
还有达里尔  萨沙  亚伯拉罕
And Daryl, Sasha, Abraham.
我也希望他们现在回来了
I wanted them back by now.
我也想处理那些尸体
I wanted those things gone.
我只是想再等等
I just wanted to wait.
你说可能会花些时间
You said it could go on a while.
我说过  的确有可能
I did and it could.
瑞克  已经过了很久了
Rick, it already has.
他们或许还活着
They could still be alive.
我们不会无视这点
We're not moving past that.
但是
You know, it's just--
此时此刻
right here, in this moment...
这就是现实
this is it, this is what it is.
"现在的生活就是这样"
"This is what life looks like now."
你听说了
You heard about that?
我不是说没有未来
I wasn't saying there wasn't a future.
一定有的
There's gotta be.
告诉我还有未来
Tell me there's more.